<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>2022.12.08</CreaDate><CreaTime>14344500</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><imsContentType export="False"></imsContentType></itemProps></DataProperties><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>NAP</ArcGISProfile></Esri><dataIdInfo><idPurp>The DEP F-Library series of elevation data are watershed-scale, high-resolution rasters that have been minorly hydro-conditioned to remove artifacts of the LiDAR collection process. These data should be considered 'bare earth data' and are suitable for large scale examination of the landscape using a variety of terrain analysis methods and visualization techniques.</idPurp><idAbs>The DEP F-Library series of elevation data are LiDAR point-cloud derived, 'high-resolution' rasters that have been partially hydro-conditioned. The F-Library series of elevation data have been assembled using the USGS HUC12 watershed framework. These data should be considered 'high-resolution bare earth' and are suitable for large scale examination of the landscape using terrain analysis methods. Two production processes were used in the development of these data, see below. The first process involves creating a digital elevation model (DEM) from the raw LiDAR point cloud data. Bare-earth elevation points are imported into an ESRI Terrain dataset using custom pyramid and thinning settings to reduce unnecessary points. The Terrain is then converted into an DEM and elevation differences smaller than 1 centimeter (cm) are truncated. This centimeter-resolution DEM is analyzed for flow characteristics to remove artifacts of processing the LiDAR that are singular “pits” in the surface. These pits are, in essence, one-cell sinks or depressions of one-cell extent that cannot be resolved using traditional processing techniques available in ArcGIS. The “pit filling” process removes all one-cell sinks. The result of the “pit filling” process is a partially hydro-conditioned DEM with one cell pits filled. The “hole punched” DEMs are moved into the P-series DEM library.</idAbs><idCredit>The results of this tool are a product of the Daily Erosion Project. The DEP is administered by the Iowa State University's Iowa Water Center.</idCredit><idCitation><resTitle>DEP DEM Pit Fill</resTitle></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>elevation</keyword><keyword>DEM</keyword><keyword>hydro-conditioning</keyword></searchKeys><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"></languageCode></dataLang><dataChar><CharSetCd value="004"></CharSetCd></dataChar><resMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="009"></MaintFreqCd></maintFreq></resMaint><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="001"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="006"/></tpCat><tpCat><TopicCatCd value="008"/></tpCat></dataIdInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdFileID>90C0AA05-818C-47B6-9A71-8EE819284170</mdFileID><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"></languageCode><countryCode value="US"></countryCode></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20220203</mdDateSt><mdContact xmlns=""><editorSource>external</editorSource><editorDigest>af2d98273b836d032358ee77296979329f5da4ac</editorDigest><rpIndName>DEP Support</rpIndName><rpOrgName>Daily Erosion Project</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Database Manager</rpPosName><rpCntInfo xmlns=""><cntAddress addressType="both"><delPoint>3321 Elings Hall, 605 Bissell Rd</delPoint><city>Ames</city><adminArea>Iowa</adminArea><postCode>50011</postCode><eMailAdd>bkgelder@iastate.edu</eMailAdd><country>US</country></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><editorSave>True</editorSave><displayName>DEP Support</displayName><role><RoleCd value="007"></RoleCd></role></mdContact><mdMaint xmlns=""><maintFreq><MaintFreqCd value="009"></MaintFreqCd></maintFreq></mdMaint></metadata>
